Professional Summary

Enthusiastic teacher-techie with notable achievements in writing. I trained as a professor in my early career, then switched to software development upon living with Computer Science Ph.D. students. As a developer, I respect best practices: I aim for simplicity, extensibility, and modularity in my software architecture. My approachability allows me to cultivate strong professional relationships with fellow employees, and my patience and persistence facilitate quick learning of new technologies.

- o 1.5 years professional programming experience in Java, Python, and SQL
- o 3+ years experience in the tech industry and related fields
- o Three published books: capable of managing and completing long-term projects
- o Effective communication: #1-ranked Teaching Assistant in my department
- o Extensive research capabilities; self-driven and resourceful

Professional Experience

Junior Software Engineer, CrossCheck inc.

October 2018 – April 2020

(Laid off due to the COVID shutdown)

- Desktop, web application, and database development in Java / Java EE, Spring, and SQL Server
- Agile methodology: Getting Things Done, Waterfall, Kanban
- VCS: Mercurial (hg) + BitBucket
- Contribute to major overhaul of company network security and sensitive data storage policies
- Projects: Focus, Whisper, TeamBuilder, KeyMaker

Logistics Coordinator, ANFT

January – October 2018

- Light web development: build and manage new company website
- Manage UI/UX across main and affiliate sites
- Streamline operations processes and develop more efficient models for tracking memberships, materials, and products

Compliance Analyst, Optio Solutions (a CrossCheck subsidiary)

January 2017 - April 2017

- Analyze Collections communications for legal and internal compliance
- Document violations and recommend disciplinary actions

Education Coordinator / Safari Guide, Safari West

June 2016 – January 2018

- Research and coordinate materials for public education
- Organize, manage, and educate groups of visitors on tours

Graduate Teaching Assistant, UC Santa Cruz

September 2014 – July 2016

- Facilitate and assist undergraduate level courses; deliver regular lectures
- Grade coursework, evaluate student performance, and determine final grades

Project Administrator, 7Layers inc.

June 2013 - September 2014

- Technical writing: Creating product documentation that conveys technical information in a language that is accessible to both internal and external users
- Design specifications for equipment testing; construct test plans for field laboratory testing of electronic equipment such as flagship cell phones, GPS equipment, alarm systems, WIFI devices
- Advise Project Managers on testability and performance of new projects prior to lab entry;
 advise lab technicians on functionality and test specifications of incoming projects

Test Laboratory Technician, 7Layers inc.

June 2012 – June 2013

- Operate Radio Frequency, OTA, LTE, Radiation, Spurious Emission, and Protocol systems that perform batteries of tests on new electronic devices
- Analyze results and provide consultations to customer-companies and project managers

Skills

Programming: Java / Java EE / JavaFX, Python, SQL, JavaScript / HTML / CSS
Software: Websphere, Tomcat, Postman, IntelliJ IDEA, SceneBuilder, Microsoft SQL Server / SSRS,
Mercurial, GitHub, BitBucket, Zendesk, Access, Excel, WebFlow

Education

Master of Arts in American History; secondary field in Political Science

Career specialization: postsecondary educator University of California, Santa Cruz

Bachelor of Arts in European History

Achievements: University Honors; Honors in the Major University of California, Santa Cruz

Publications

I am a horror author whose work has been optioned for a Hollywood film deal.

Blackwell, Felix. "A Gift from Below." Chilling Tales for Dark Nights, Craig Groshek et al. 2019.

Blackwell, Felix. In the Devil's Dreams (CreateSpace, 2019).

Blackwell, Felix. Stolen Tongues (CreateSpace, 2017).

Blackwell, Felix. The Cold People and Other Fairy Tales from Nowhere (CreateSpace, 2016).

References available upon request